# AKHIL REDDY

 $+1(469) 6597139 \diamond \text{Columbus, OH}$ 

Edara.akhilreddy@gmail.com \lefthanton https://www.linkedin.com/in/akhil-reddy-98412b265/ \lefthanton https://www.linkedin.com/in/akhil-reddy-98412b265/

## **OBJECTIVE**

Experienced software developer with over three years of involvement in the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), adeptly contributing to all phases. Interested in positions involving product ownership and project management, and Graduated Master's degree in IT with a specialization in Business Management. I am currently seeking career opportunities in both contract and full-time roles.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master of Information Technology, University of Memphis

2022 - 2023

Coursework:- Depth in HTML CSS, React Advanced, Programming with JavaScript, Version Control, AWS Cloud Technical Essentials, Migrating to the AWS Cloud, Scrum Masters

## **SKILLS**

Technical Skills Soft Skills Methodologies  ${\it Java, ReactJS, React-native, python, HTML, CSS, tailwind-CSS, Spring, MySQL, Azure, AWS, Git. and the property of the pro$ 

Communication, Problem-solving, teamwork, Time management, Continuous Learning

Agile, Waterfall

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Pristenit INC

## Software Engineer

May 2023 - Present

Dallas, TX

• Optimized performance in a React Native app by refactoring complex components, resulting in a 30percent reduction in loading times and performance monitoring tools.

- Developing a web page using HTML5, SCSS, React, Flux, Nodejs, Typescript, JavaScript, MongoDB.
- Creating new futures, functionality, and capability for client web site.
- Worked with DBAs in designing the database Triggers, Views and Indexes to implement optimized SQL queries.
- Manage and support customer environments in Microsoft Azure cloud.

## Analyst [Master's project]

University of Memphis

Jan 2022 - May 2023

Memphis, TN

- Developed complex SQL queries and utilized Excel and data visualization tools to create meaningful reports and dashboards.
- Utilized Tableau to design and develop interactive dashboards and reports, providing insights on key business metrics and performance indicators.
- Solid understanding of database management and querying using SQL, Excellent problem-solving, gathering data, and critical-thinking skills.

#### Software Engineer

May2018 - Nov 2021

India

Jasam Technologies

- Worked in all phases of SDLC such as requirements gathering, designing, developing, testing, and deploying, and Involved in developing mobile applications for both IOS and Android platforms by using React-Native.
- Used Tailwind CSS with react-native for styling and Google API for GPS navigation. React native Elements to elevate app designs
- Experience integrating push notification services like Apple Push Notification Service (APNS) into React Native applications, enabling real-time communication with users.
- Proficient in designing and developing RESTful Web APIs to enable communication between client-side and server-side applications.

• Designed and implementation of public and private facing websites on AWS Cloud.

## **PROJECTS**

**Payment Processing API** Developed a RESTful API using Java, Spring Boot, and Apace CXF for processing payments, ensuring secure and efficient transactions. Utilized Web Sockets for real-time communication. Customer Dashboard: Built a customer dashboard application using Angular, Spring Boot, and Oracle database, providing real-time insights and enabling data-driven decision-making.

**Supply chain optimization:** For the transportation we need to analyze the data, Then I have Created a data model in Snowflake that reflects the transportation operations. That can include tables for shipping routes, carrier information, transit times, fuel costs, and delivery times. I need to define the relationships between these tables and set up any necessary constraints, such as foreign key constraints.

Integrate the transportation data into Snowflake using ETL (extract, transform, load) processes. I have used Talend tool to automate this process and ensure that the data is accurate and up to date. Used Snowflake's integration with Tableau to create dashboards and reports that communicate my findings. For analyze the transportation data and to identify opportunities to reduce costs I have used Snowflake's SQL.